Guide to the Franci Jarrard collection, 1977-1980, 2004-2017 MS 708
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Franci Jarrard collection
1977-1980
2004-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Jarrard, Franci Files
MS 708
36.1 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0708aip_001 (36.1 GB)
11.7 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0708aip_002 (11.7 GB)
This collection consists of digital audio files and images.
Biographical / Historical
Born and raised in Houston, Franci Files began hanging out at Sand Mountain Coffee House in the late 1960s. She befriended members of the community including Guy and Susanna Clark, Townes Van Zandt, Don Sanders, and Vince Bell.
A few years later after graduating from college, she became one of the co-owners of Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. As one of the crew, she organized and handled food preparation, specifically the spaghetti lunches.
As the 1980s approached, Franci Files married Stephen Jarrard and began to explore her own musical career. She teamed up with her husband as a duo, performed in the band Terry and the Telephones, and lent vocals to Richard Dobson's second album, "The Big Taste."
Ready for a change, in the early 1980s, Franci and Stephen Jarrard relocated to the Austin-area. They continued to explore their music. Franci Jarrard started to play the accordion and performed with Richard Dobson when he played in Texas. In the 1990s, Stephen and Franci participated in the strolling trios Europa Trio with Javier Chaparro and Troika with Ann Mesrobian.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of digital audio files and images documenting the Houston folk scene of the 1970s-1980.
Conditions Governing Access
Request access to this digital material (stored on Fondren Library's nearline / non-public server) by contacting Woodson Research Center staff at woodson@rice.edu. Please use the Identifier number in your request. This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Franci Jarrard in September 2017.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Women
Document Types
Folk music; Folk-rock music
Subjects (Persons)
Bell, Vince; Cade, Bill; Jarrard, Stephen; Dobson, Richard J.; Sanders, Don; Van Zandt, Townes; Lovett, Lyle
- Series I: Audio
  - Vince Bell, 1977-11
    Scope and Contents
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Vince Bell playing live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Roll Me Easy," "Nothin'," "What a Change She's Made in Me," "Oklahoma Wind," "From Your Eyes," "Slowly Goes the Motion," "Ladance at the Last Chance Saloon," "All through My Days," "Me and Loretta," "Even Cowboys Get the Blues," "I Shall Be Released," "Willin'," "Long Distance Lover," "Guacamole Queen," "I've Come to See Your Truck"
  - Bill Cade, 1978-07-24
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Cade "a live in the living room" recording. Tracks include: "Cottonfields," "Roll Me Easy," "Saturday," "Storm on the River," "Tennessee Stud," "Song Bird," "It's a Sin," "Balloon Man," "Sweet Misery"
  - Bill Cade and Stephen Jarrard, 1978-09
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Cade and Stephen Jarrard live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Sailin' Shoes," "Close Encounters," "Hotel Mirabella, "A Political Blues," "Ships at Sea," "Black Mountain Rag," "Poor Pitiful Me," "Saturday," "Let's Get Lost in the Lights Tonite," "Lay Down Sally," "Rodeo Man," "Paradise," "Berkley Woman"
  - Stephen Jarrard and Franci Files, Bill Cade, 1978-12
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain songs by Stephen Jarrard and Franci Files on "The Little Ol' Show That Comes on After Monty Python" and Bill Cade with Stephen Jarrard. Tracks include: "Morning Breeze," "Last Dance at the Last Chance Saloon," "Pineapple and Rum," "Merry Go Round," "Angels in Disguise," "Railroad Blues," "Saturday," "Tenessee Stud" "A Woman's Place," "Berkley Woman," "Paradise," "Good Night Irene," "So Long Honey Bare," "In Love with a Good Woman," "Doing the Best You Can," "Don't Let the Sunshine Fool You," "Gotta Get Back to Texas," "Hey Saturday," "Big River" - Not all tracks listed.
  - Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant Favorites, part 1, 1978
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain songs by Stephen Jarrard and Franci Files, Eric Taylor, and Bill Cade.
  - Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant Favorites, part 2, 1978
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain songs by Eric Taylor and Bill Cade.
  - Crystal Egg - Bill Cade, 1979-03
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Cade on the Crystal Egg radio show hosted by Roger Ruffcorn.
  - Bill Staines and Bill Cade, 1979-06
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Staines and Bill Cade and Joe Romano live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Rosville Fair," "Rodeo Rose," "Last Thing on My Mind," "Old Silver," "Phoenix," "Lovers and Losers," "Do Re Mi," "Roll Alabama Roll," "Yodel Song," "Up and Away," "Good Nite," "All God's Critters"
  - Local Folk, Summer 1979
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain songs by Bill Cade, Eric Taylor, John Grimaudo, and Stephen Jarrard.
  - Local Folk, Summer 1979
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain songs by Stephen Jarrard, Eric Taylor, Bill Cade, John Grimaudo, and Linda Lowe [?] recorded live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: 1st track is missing, "Rooty Toot Toot," "Joselin Jocelyn," "Angels in Disguise," "Shoe Shine Boy," "France Blues," "Losing / Willing," "Mooney," "By and By," "Good Mornin' Blues," "Sun Down Blues," "Boats," "Game of Hearts," "Cocaine," "Viper," "Goin' Down to Baltimore," "Sweet Misery," "Lay Down Sally," "Take Five," Track 20 guitar tuning, "Company"
  - Crystal Egg - Richard Dobson, 1979
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Richard Dobson on the Crystal Egg radio show hosted by Roger Ruffcorn.
  - The Horse's Mouth, Dr. Rockit, 1980-03-18
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain The Horse's Mouth and Dr. Rockit playing live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Hear Those Jungle Drums," "The Blues Won't Take You by Surprise," "Tossing and Turning," "Midnight Hour," "I Love the Woman," "Signifying Monkey," "Hey Pocky-Way," "Walking the Dog," "Route 66," "Mornin' Rain," "Road Runner," "Money," "Anyday Now"
  - Terry and the Telephones, 1980-03
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Terry and the Telephones playing live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Bright City Lights," "New World," "Something Good," "Tan Shoes and Pink Shoelaces," "Just Gimme Some Kind of Sign," "Little Sister," "So Fine," "Tonite's the Nite," "Hooked on Love," "What Can I Do," "Together Again," "Hats," "Walk with the Wild West End," "Tan Shoes and Pink Shoelaces," "Bright City Lites," "Good Clean Fun," "A Woman's World," "Let the Good Times Roll," "Tune into Heaven," "Give Me Your Love in a Song"
  - Cypress Swamp Stompers, 1980-04-08
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain the Cypress Swamp Stompers live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Sniff," "Red Man," "Georgia Brown," "Beggar Man," "Footprints in the Snow," "Dog's Rag," "My Windown Faces South," "This Heart Is Mine," "Miss Mollie," "Jersualem Ridge," "White Oak Stomp," "Palmadell [ sp?] Portal Service"
  - John Grimaudo and Dr. Rockit, 1980-05-22
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain John Grimaudo and Dr. Rockit live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant.
  - Dr. Rockit, 1980-05
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Dr. Rockit live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. There are 3 CD tracks, but ? songs. Songs include: "?"; "Hey Pocky A-Way"; "Come on Dance"; "Lean Mean, But Good"; "High Blood Pressure"; "Signifying Monkey"; "The Blues Stew"; "The Tighten Up"; "96 Tears"; "Louie Louie"; "Jailhouse Rock"; "School Day"; "Dr. Feelgood"; "Road Runner"; "Money"; "I Love the Woman"; "Gimme Some Lovin'"; "Twist and Shout"
  - Rick, André, Pete, and Jerry, 1980
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain songs by Rick, André, Pete, and Jerry in Houston. Tracks include: "Mr. Blue," "How Come You Don't Want What You Got", "Ballad of Hank and Rita," "Full Time Woman," "Spittin' in the Wind"
  - Bill Cade and friends, 2004-12-31
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Cade and friends playing live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant.
  - Rat Creek, 2008-08-01
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain the Rat Creek songs: "Where the Old Gret Divide Starts the Young Rio Grande," "Backyard," "Cat in the Window," "Don't Cork That Bottle," "Evant Stockyards," "Everyone's Full," "Jug Band Music," "Ripple in Still Water," "Intro," "Steel Guitar Rag," "Back Street Girl," "White Freight Liner," "Stranded," "Goin' Back to Texas," "Truck Drivin' Man," "Banjoy Song," "In the Jailhouse Now," "Old Kentucky Home," "Anyone Who Must Leave Us," "Weekend," "Fade." Songs recorded at the Old Quarter, Saxon Pub, Rat Manor, and by Pete Gorisch, primarily from 1971-1973.
  - Aileen and Elkin
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain a live performance by Aileen and Elkin at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "Jolie Girl," "Country Girl," "Back to the Hills," "Paradise," "Living Country Style," "Starving Miners," "Love Is a Rose," "Squealie's Love," "Sidewalk Man," "For You," "Regina," "Cowboys"
  - Vince Bell, n.d.
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Vince Bell playing live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: 1- "Oklahoma Wind," 2 - "Words and Games," 3 - "Roll Me Easy / Mississippi Memory," 4 - "Slowly," 5 - "Train Whore," 6 - "Any Day Now," 7 - "The Blue Moon Lounge," 8 - "I Shall Be Released," 9 - "?" 10 - Audience cheering 11 - "Rainbow," 12 - "Coreena"
  - Bill Cade, n.d.
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Cade. Tracks include: "26 Miles," "Fannin Street," "If It Wasn't for the Wind," "Trouble in Mind," "Pollin'," "Saturday," "It's a Sin," "American Dream," "Ace," "Heart of N'Orleans," "Down the Road," "I'll Be Your Baby Tonite," "Camp Hambone," "Auld Lang Syne"
  - Bill Cade, n.d.
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Cade in the living room. Tracks include: "Too Long in the City," "Homemade Kites," "Trouble in Mind," "Good Mornin' Blues," "Heart of New Orleans," "Twenty Six Miles," "If Only I Hadn't Loved You So Well," "Balloon Man"
  - Crystal Egg - Lyle Lovett, n.d.
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Lyle Lovett on the Crystal Egg radio show hosted by Roger Ruffcorn.
  - Crystal Egg - Don Sanders
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Don Sanders on the Crystal Egg radio show hosted by Roger Ruffcorn.
  - Crystal Egg - Nobart and Grimaudo
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Nobart and John Grimaudo on the Crystal Egg radio show hosted by Roger Ruffcorn.
  - Crystal Egg - Hemmer Ridge Mountain Boys, n.d.
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Hemmer Ridge Mountain Boys on the Crystal Egg radio show hosted by Roger Ruffcorn.
  - John Grimaudo, n.d.
    The audio tracks for this CD are corrupted. We only have a record of the tracks, which include: "Tree Balling Blues," "Police Dog Blues," "Take Five," "Chesterfield Blues," "Last Fair Deal," "Wing and a Prayer," "Rampart Street," "Terrible [?] Blues"
  - Stephen Jarrard and Franci Files
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Stephen Jarrard and Franci Files live at Hard Thymes Soup Kitchen. Tracks include: "Cakewalk," "Louisiana Man," "I Ain't Gonna Think about Trouble Anymore," "Hey Mr. Spaceman," "Circus Life," "May You Never," "Sailing Shoes," "Sweet Sweet Shine," "Jesus on the Main Line," Track 10 dead air, "Too Long in the City," "Last Dance at the Last Chance Saloon," "Silver Track," "The Boats They Come They Go," "If the Blues," "The Blues Won't Take You By Surprise," "Living on Tulsa Time," "I'm Goin' Fishing," "Do Re Me," "End"
  - Bill Staines, n.d.
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Bill Staines live at Friendly Folk. Tracks include: "Old Jack," "A Tree in Nebraska," "Cayote My Old Friend," "Yodel Song," "Oklahoma Bound," "Roseville Fair," "Jolie Girl, "The Boats," "Miles Upon Your Shoes," "North Land," "For a Dancer," "Crazy Leslie," "Hauling in the Wood," "Hard Times," "The Red Clay Country Blues," "Repaint You Thinners," "Where I Live"
  - Townes Van Zandt with Mickey White
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav and one access copy mp3. Audio files contain Townes Van Zandt with Mickey White playing live at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. Tracks include: "All I Got Is Yesterday," "Dollar Bill Blues," "Don't Take It So Bad," "Snowing on Ratton," "Pancho and Lefty," "Sometimes It Happens That Way," "When I'm Gone," "Loretta," "White Freight Liner," "The Cuckoo," "The Indian Cowboy," "The Girls"
- Series II: Images
  - Rat Creek CD scans, 2008-08-01
    These digitized image files consist of one master copy tif and one access copy jpg.
  - Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant calendars, 1970s-1980
    These digitized image files consist of one master copy tif and one access copy jpg. Images include calendars for April, May (2), November, and December.
- Series III: Oral history
  - Franci Jarrard and Lyse Moore video oral history, 2017-09-08
    These born digital video files consist of one master copy mov and one access copy located at scholarship.rice.edu.